Three minutes, 31, 32…
3分31秒 32秒…
Hey, let's stop for today.
今天就训练到这里吧
Okay.
好
But I want to do a little more.
但我还想再练习一下
See ya.
辛苦了
You went to apologize at the store?
你去便利店道歉了？
Yeah, I found out if you pay and apologize,
是 我查过了 如果好好付钱和道歉
some places won't report you, so…
有些店不会报警 所以我…
-How did it go? -Well…
-结果呢？ -这个嘛…
Sakuragi, he…
樱木他…
Oh, that? A guy who looked like a teacher paid.
这个啊？有个像老师的人已经付了
-A teacher? -What did he say?
-老师？ -他叫什么来着？
Really tall, with piercing eyes.
很高 有双锐利的眼睛
-Was it Sakuragi? -Oh, yeah.
-是不是樱木？ -啊 对！
He said he wanted to check the security footage.
他说他想看监控录像
Don't tell anyone, but he took it away.
不要跟别人说 但他拿走了
The security footage?
监控录像？
Why?
为什么？
-Why did he? -He just wanted your shoplifting footage.
-他为什么这么做？ -他当然是想要你的偷窃录像
That guy…
那家伙…
What's he going to do?
到底想做什么？
Did they come today?
他们今天有来吗？
Unfortunately, no.
很遗憾 没有
Yesterday, their homeroom teacher went to talk to them, but…
昨天班主任找了他们谈话 也有去他们家里劝说 但…
Good grief, we were so proud of our zero-truancy record.
真是的 我们之前为 零旷课记录那么骄傲
All of our reforms are destroyed because of Sakuragi.
我们之前的改革 因为这个樱木都被毁了
But Mr. Sakuragi did that to Kohashi and Iwai
但是樱木老师这样对小桥和岩井
because they were at fault.
是因为他们有错在先
He went too far. And now they're staying home.
他做得太过分了 现在他们躲在家里
They've closed themselves off!
可以说关上心门了
Yes, um…
这个嘛…
Next time, if Mr. Sakuragi causes trouble,
下次樱木再闯祸
you will also take responsibility.
你也得负责任
Of course. I intend to.
当然 我有这个打算
Pardon me.
失陪了
He's so cheeky for a vice principal.
作为教导主任 他可真是厚脸皮
Forget that. Is this why you betrayed me at the board meeting?
别提那个了 你在理事会背叛我就是因为这个吗？
-This…this is… -Are you gay?
-这…这是… -你是男同志？
-I knew it. -Chairman…
-我就知道 -理事长…
Silly. Behind the times, aren't we?
笨蛋 现在都什么年代了？
These days LGBT is normal. It's the diversity era!
现在性少数很常见 这是多元化的时代！
But…
但是…
We educators, we're supposed to teach that to the children!
我们是教育者 本应是教导学生理解这点的人
But you're embarrassed and try to hide it.
但你却觉得太羞愧 想要隐藏
And you let yourself be threatened. Idiot!
还让自己被威胁了 太笨了！
Be confident!
抬头挺胸做自己吧
But that's not what Sakuragi threatened me with…
但这不是樱木拿来威胁我的事…
No… Did you pay for that macho man?
不会吧…难道你带那个肌肉男出场？
No, no, no. You see…
不！怎么可能…
Nonsense!
太荒谬了！
Really?
真的吗？
He, uh, was low on cash, so I gave him a little spending money.
他…有点缺钱 所以我给了他些生活费
You massive idiot!
你这个大白痴！
Don't do it again! That behavior leads to misunderstandings.
别再做这种引人误会的事了
Yes ma'am! Never again.
是！再也不会了！
-Watch Sakuragi. -Yes!
-观察好樱木 -是
I will ensure he doesn't cause any more problems…
我保证他不会再惹麻烦了
Oh, he can cause problems.
他可以惹麻烦哦
Hey, Take. Let's go early.
嘿 小竹 我们赶紧去吧
Will the Iwa-Kiyo duo get picked?
岩清组合会被选上场吗？
It depends on the match-up, I guess?
这个嘛 要看对手是谁吧？
If Kimitsunishi High doesn't play, they might not be.
如果君津西高中不上场 第一天也许会保留实力
I want to see them play. Especially Iwasaki.
我好期待看她们上场 尤其是岩崎
Me too!
我也是！
They're so loud. I can't sleep.
他们太吵啦 我没法睡
The badminton club tournament members are being announced.
羽球社今天会宣布参加比赛的选手
It's amazing. The whole school's watching.
真是厉害 全校都在关注
-Huh? -Kaede.
-咦？ -枫
-What's wrong? -Nothing.
-怎么了？ -没事
-Let's nail the tournament. -Yeah, let's.
-一起加油 拿下这个大赛吧 -嗯 加油
-See you there. -Okay.
-待会见了 -好
SHOPLIFTER
（我知道你做了什么 小偷）
What's going on? Something happen?
怎么了？发生了什么事吗？
This was in my locker.
这在我的储物柜里
"I know what you did."
“我知道你做了什么”
"Shoplifter."
“小偷”
Who would do this?
谁会这么做？
It's gotta be him.
一定是他
Give it.
给我
What are you trying to do with this?
你想用这个来干嘛？
You even got the security footage. What are you going to do?
你还拿了监控录像 你打算干什么？
Oh, that video.
哦 那个录像
Please give it back.
请把它还来
What are you going to do about this tournament?
这次比赛你有什么打算？
I'm playing.
我会参加
Don't. You can't.
别去 你赢不了的
My spot at Seinan depends on this tournament.
我青南大学的推荐名额 就靠这次比赛了
I can't quit. It's impossible.
我不能退出 绝对不可能
Huh. Do what you want.
嗯 随便你吧
-Hang on… -Kaede!
-等一下… -枫！
He's going to ruin me.
他会毁掉我
My life will be ruined.
我的人生会被毁掉
Team competition, first round. Doubles first game.
团体赛第一轮 双打第一场
Iwasaki and Kiyono.
岩崎和清野
Next, Okamoto and Abe.
接下来 冈本和阿部
First singles match, Yoshikawa, then Kiyono.
单打赛第一场吉川 接着清野
Last is Iwasaki.
最后是岩崎
We can win the first round. The problem is the next one.
我们绝对能拿下第一轮 问题在下一轮
Kimitsunishi will win.
君津西高中也会赢
Their doubles, Yamano and Ukita, are ranked second in the prefecture.
他们的双打山野和浮田 在县里排名第二
They'll play the number one pair, Iwasaki and Kiyono.
他们会对阵我们的第一组岩崎和清野
Coming to see this match, is Kashiwagi from Seinan,
来观赛的 有青南大学的柏木教练
and other top university coaches.
还有其它顶尖大学的教练
This is where your lives are decided.
这是决定你们命运的比赛
Defeat them.
打败她们
Yes, sir.
是
Kiyono, concentrate!
清野 专注！
Iwasaki, run!
岩崎 快跑！
Run!
跑啊！
Get it, get it. Keep running!
接球 接着跑！
Get it! Run, run!
接球！跑！
Next is right!
下一个在右边！
Kaede's really amazing.
枫真的好厉害
Of course, they say she's Olympic material.
当然了 他们说她是参加奥运会的料
I wanna try too.
我也想试试看
Huh?
咦？
Iwasaki, go!
岩崎 接球！
I want to devote myself to something like Kaede.
我想像枫一样 全力投入某件事
That really impacted me.
我真的好震惊
Mr. Sakuragi's speech. Ugly and stupid, lazy and slow.
樱木那天说的话 又笨又丑 懒惰又迟钝
-Oh, that was… -But I was happy.
-那是… -但我很高兴
Huh?
咦？
For the first time in my life, I got scolded.
这是我人生中第一次被骂
I've never even been scolded by my parents.
我从来没被父母骂过
So I was like, "Wow, some adults really care."
所以那时我觉得 “哇 有些大人真的会为了你发火”
Until now, I can't remember ever working hard for something.
我直到现在都不曾为什么事情努力过
I never continued private lessons or school clubs.
才艺班或学校的社团 我都半途而废了
Everyone would be like, "That's okay!"
老师们和父母只会说“没关系”
But I feel like here, I could work hard or something.
但在这里 我想我可以为某些事努力
Isn't that a weird reason to apply to UTokyo?
作为申请东大的理由是不是很奇怪？
Not at all! Any reason will do at first.
完全不会！ 作为开始的理由 什么都可以
Yay! We got our second person.
太好了！我们有第二位学员啦
I've been listening. What a selfish reason.
我刚刚就听到了 真是自私的理由啊
I can't sleep.
我睡不了
Are you living there?
你该不会住在那里吧？
Sorry, it's distracting, right?
抱歉 你果然会很在意吧
Who are you?
你是谁？
This is Nao Hayase. She wants to join us.
这位是早濑菜绪 她想加入我们
We've got some strange students.
我们的学生真是奇怪
You should say "eager".
你应该说“热切”
Thank you for having me.
请多多指教
Let me say one thing.
让我先说一件事
-You too, Amano. -Huh?
-天野 你也是 -咦？
Don't tell your parents you're in the UTokyo course.
你们正在上东大专科这件事 别让你们的父母知道
-Huh? -I can't stand fussing.
-咦？ -我不想被烦
Sir.
老师
Sheesh.
哎哟
Alright, first we'll have a test.
好 我们首先来个测试
-Already? -You'll take this.
-那么快？ -你们先做这个
Last year's Common Test for University Admissions.
去年的大学入学共通考试
That's the big January test. No way. I can't.
那是一月的大考试 不行 绝对办不到
It's too sudden…
我也是 这太突然了…
It's okay. The purpose is to get data on where your academic level is now.
没关系的 目的是得到 你们成绩水平的数据而已
Data?
数据？
What's the first step to UTokyo?
考上东大的第一个条件就是
-Know thyself. -Know thyself?
-认识自己 -认识自己？
Where's your level now? Where do you stand nationwide?
你目前的水平在哪？ 你全国排名的位置是？
Which subjects are you good at? Which need work?
你哪科比较强？哪科需要多努力？
We need subjective data
我们得先取得所有数据 客观了解自己
to make a strategy for your exam.
来为你们制定备考策略
Here's today's schedule and tomorrow's.
这是今天的时间表 以及明天的
Five subjects and seven exams in two days?
两天内完成五科七门考试？
Yes, just like the real test.
对 就和正式考试一样
Seriously? Sounds harsh.
认真的吗？也太难了吧
Stop complaining. Here we go.
别抱怨了 我们开始吧
Three, two, one.
三、二、一
Start!
开始！
SHAME ON YOU
（你没资格打羽球 你真可耻）
QUIT BADMINTON SHOPLIFTER
（别打羽球了 小偷）
Again…
又来了…
Alright, you're done. Good work.
好 结束 辛苦啦
I can't do this. I can't think.
我做不下去了 我无法思考
You both worked hard. We'll do the rest after lunch tomorrow.
你们两位都努力了 剩下的我们明天午餐后再继续
-Rest well today. -Tomorrow? That's depressing.
-今天好好休息吧 -明天还有？真让人忧郁…
I know you can't do it now. You can improve by next year.
我知道你现在做不了 我们目标是在明年拿下高分
I think I'll quit.
还是退出吧
Huh?
什么？
It's not for me.
这不适合我
I'm not trying out for UTokyo.
我还是不考东大了
-Hayase! -Sorry. Goodbye.
-早濑 -不好意思 再见
Hey, hey Hayase!
等一下 早濑！
Hey, Hayase.
喂 早濑！
What was that about? Giving up so fast.
怎么回事？那么快就放弃
-Leave it. -But…
-别管了 -但是…
This is on the house. From my sister.
这是免费的 我姐姐请客
Huh?
咦？
Wow, thanks. Thank you very much.
真是不好意思 谢谢你
You always help my brother so much.
不会 我弟弟麻烦你们关照了
Please enjoy it.
请享用
Hayase already quit?
早濑退出了？
Yeah. After one day!
对呀 才一天耶
Well, that's who she is.
这个嘛 她就是这样的人
AMANO SORRY. I QUIT.
（对不起 我要退出）
-Seriously? Why? -Amano quit too?
-不是吧？为什么？ -天野也退出？
I thought he was promising.
我还以为他有希望
-It's too bad. -This is your problem too.
-真可惜 -这也是你的问题
I can't just stand by and let them quit.
我不能这样看着他们退出
I'll make a call.
我去打个电话
Tell those guys it's about time they showed up at school.
喂 和那些家伙说 他们是时候来学校了
-Huh? -Iwai and Kohashi.
-什么？ -岩井和小桥
You made their video, didn't you?
他们的视频是你剪的 对吧？
It used the same editing app as this video.
它用了和这视频一样的剪辑软件
I'm the culprit just for that?
只因为这个 我就成了共犯？
I have other reasons.
还有其它原因
I should ask what you're doing.
我才应该问你在做什么
You got that video from the store security camera.
你拿了便利店那段监控录像
Are you blackmailing students?
你在威胁学生吗？
Maybe.
可能吧
Akira, a delivery. To Iida's house.
辉 送餐 去饭田家
Okay.
好
Where are they heading?
他们要去哪？
Mizuno speaking. Yes, I'm still here.
我是水野 是的 我还在
-Whoa! -What?
-哦！ -什么？
I'll go right away.
是 我马上过去
-Let's go. Thanks! -What is it?
-走吧 谢谢！ -怎么了？
Let's go.
快走吧
Seto, you're here too.
濑户 你也在这啊
I heard sirens on my way back.
我回来的路上听到警笛
It's awful, isn't it?
真是糟糕 对吧？
Mr. Sakuragi, Ms. Mizuno.
樱木老师 水野老师
Over here!
这里！
Yes!
是！
Sorry, excuse me. Let me through.
不好意思 借过一下 让我过去
Sorry, pardon me.
不好意思
It was the Special Course room?
不会吧 烧的是东大专科那间教室？
Yes.
是
Hey, hey, hey!
喂
It burned up!
根本烧光了
-This here is okay. -Why?!
-这里没问题 -搞什么？
All my worldly possessions!
我的所有财产！
It's all ashes now.
都化为灰烬了
Really… Could you be a bit more considerate of others?
真是的…你能不能考虑一下其他人？
One thing after another, I can't even sleep well.
接二连三的 我都睡不好觉了
Come now, Ms. Tamura
田村老师 请来一下
The firemen just left.
消防员刚刚离开了
They say the cause was a cigarette.
他们说火源是香烟
What do you think you're doing?
你到底是想干嘛？
Smoking in a hallowed classroom!
在神圣的教室里吸烟
He doesn't smoke in the room.
他不在室内吸烟的
Who other than him?
除了他还有谁？
Anyway, camping in the school is disgusting.
无论如何 在学校里扎营真是恶心
I gave my permission. It's part of his style.
这是我批准的 这是他的风格
Yes, he's more passionate than anyone, staying onsite 24 hours a day.
是的 他比任何人都更有热忱 所以24小时都待在这里
Passionate? He fell asleep with a lit cigarette.
什么热忱？他八成是点着烟就睡着了
Yes, that's what happened. I'm sorry.
是的 事情就是这样 我很抱歉
What?
什么？
-So you admit it's your fault? -Yes.
-所以你承认这是你的错？ -是的
What are you saying?! We were at the restaurant.
你在说什么？我们当时在拉面店里
I put it out, but it must've had a spark.
我把它熄灭了 但还留着一点火花
After a while, I guess it ignited.
也许过一会之后 它燃烧了起来
But…
但是…
You're suspended until the board decides your punishment.
在理事会决定你的惩处之前 你被停职了
Get your things and leave immediately.
收拾你的东西 马上离开
-Understood. -Huh?
-我明白了 -咦？
Why did you lie like that?
你为什么说谎？
Now Mr. Takahara is put in a tough spot…
都是因为你 高原老师的处境变得…
-Mizuno, it's fine. -It's not fine!
-水野 没关系的 -有关系！
It's just like before.
这就好像之前
With Yoneyama, if you fought back, it wouldn't have turned out like that.
米山的事 如果你反击 事情就不会变成这样
You graduated from UTokyo and became a lawyer,
你从东大毕业 当了律师
but you're still very stupid.
但还是很笨
Hotel money.
旅店钱
I'm sure Mr. Sakuragi has his reasons.
樱木老师肯定有他的原因
I think he's covering for whoever did this.
我想他是在掩护做这件事的人
If the culprit is a student,
如果犯人是学生
a teacher must teach about taking responsibility.
老师应该要教他们负责任
I'll look into it.
我会调查
What, you're not hungry?
你是怎么样？你不饿吗？
No, I just had a hard practice today.
不 只是今天训练很辛苦
This is perfectly nutritionally balanced.
这个营养很均衡
Eat it all and don't waste any.
把它吃完 不要浪费
Did you drink protein after practice?
你训练后有喝乳清蛋白吗？
-Yeah. -Hey.
-嗯 -话说
How's Seinan going?
青南大学那边怎样了？
It'll come down to the next tournament.
这要看接下来的比赛
That's my daughter.
真是我女儿
If you get in with Coach Kashiwagi, the Olympics won't be far off.
要是你能进去跟着柏木教练训练 奥运会就不远了
I know.
我知道
Hey, I got an e-mail from the school.
话说 我收到了学校的电邮
There was a suspicious fire?
发生了可疑的火灾？
What will they do if it affects the tournament?
如果影响到县大赛要怎么办？
How would Kaede know?
枫怎么会知道？
Thanks for dinner. I'm tired so I'm going to bed.
我吃饱了 我太累了 先进去睡了
You better not be getting sick.
你最好别生病
She's okay. She's focusing before the tournament.
她没事 她正在为比赛集中精力
She needs time alone. Right?
需要一些独处时间 对吧？
When we were athletes, we did the same.
以前当运动员时 我们也是这样的
The UTokyo Special Course is down to zero students.
东大专科的学生人数降到零位
Correct. I can't wait for tomorrow's board meeting.
是 我真期待明天的理事会议
Mr. Sakuragi…
樱木老师他…
I suppose it's over for him.
我想就到此为止了
You're not crushing on him, are you?
你该不是迷上他了？
-Of course not! -In the commotion after the fire.
-当然不是！ -那天火灾之后
You were making eyes at him.
你含情脉脉地看着他
Don't betray me again.
别再背叛我了
Something like that would never ever happen!
那样的事不会再发生了！
Alright then.
好吧
At any rate, the Special Course is done for.
无论如何 这个专科完了
Mizuno!
水野！
-A moment. -Yes.
-来一下 -好
-Good morning, Kaede. -Good morning.
-枫 早上好 -早上好
Huh? Nao?
奇怪 菜绪？
Get this. She already quit the UTokyo Special Course.
我说 她退出东大专科了
-Already? -It's so hard!
-那么快？ -真的太难了！
Plus, if I get busy, I can't go support you at your games.
而且如果变忙 我就没法去比赛支持你了
-That's your reason? -Anyway they had that fire.
-就因为这样？ -而且他们那里还发生了火灾
It's good you quit that UTokyo Special Course.
你退出东大专科真是退得好啊
Yeah, bad news. Smoking at school?
对啊 还真糟糕 在学校抽烟
Hayase. It's not funny.
早濑 这不好笑
It's kind of funny.
这蛮好笑的
-A security camera? -Yes.
-监控？ -是
We only have them near the exits.
我们只设置在出口附近
I was looking for a hint.
我刚刚在找线索
-Sorry, go ahead. -Got it.
-不好意思 拜托了 -没问题
Okay, look at this.
好 请看这个
No way…
不是吧…
Iwasaki! Too slow! Fifty burpees.
岩崎！太慢了 五十个立卧撑跳！
Yes, sir.
是
Extend your knees! Knees!
伸展你的膝盖！膝盖！
You're not jumping enough.
你跳得不够
A little before that fire yesterday,
这是昨天火灾发生之前
this was on the security camera footage.
监控的录像
You told me then.
你那时跟我说
You heard the noise during your delivery and came.
你送餐的时候听见了声音 所以过来
But on the video,
但这个录像里
you were already at school before the fire.
你在火灾之前 已经在学校里了
Why?
为什么？
I'm not accusing you.
我不是在指控你
I just want to know what happened.
我只是想知道发生了什么
Ma'am.
老师
That really hurts me.
真是令我受伤
You are accusing me.
你在指控我啊
It wasn't you, then?
这样的话 那不是你？
It wasn't.
不是
Okay.
好
Is that all?
这就完了吗？
There was one more person there before the fire.
火灾之前 还有另一个人在那
They were also on camera.
也被监控录下来了
I'll ask that person.
我会去问那个人
Are you okay? Kaede, you look pale.
没事吧？枫 你脸色很苍白
I'm fine. I still have practice.
我没事 我还有训练
Really? You shouldn't push it and just rest today.
真的？你不要太勉强 今天休息吧
It's got nothing to do with you.
这和你没关系
What are you saying? I'm worried about you.
你在说什么？我很担心你
I want you to play in the tournament.
我想看你在比赛…
That's so annoying.
烦死了
Stop expecting things from me.
别自己在那里抱那么大的希望
Why are you so irritable?
等一下 你怎么那么烦躁？
Watching a flake who never thinks would make anyone irritable.
看到从来不思考的怪人 谁都会觉得烦吧
Huh? All you ever think about is badminton!
什么？你自己脑子里也只有羽毛球！
It's better than having nothing.
好过什么都没有
KANTO HIGH SCHOOL BADMINTON TOURNAMENT CHIBA PREFECTURE PLAYOFFS
（关东高中羽球县大赛 千叶县预赛）
Wow, it's Tatsumi.
哇 是龙海！
-They're cool! -Up front to the right is Kaede Iwasaki.
-她们好帅！ -第一排右边的是岩崎枫
Wow, she's so cool.
哇 她真是帅
She actually showed up? That's crazy.
但她还真的来了？真糟糕
She just marches in here. Isn't she embarrassed?
这样大摇大摆走进来 难道不丢脸？
Hey, habitual shoplifter!
嘿 惯犯小偷！
Kaede Iwasaki is a shoplifter!
岩崎枫是小偷！
Hey!
喂！
What are you saying? Stop spouting nonsense.
你说什么？ 你什么意思？别胡说八道！
But in the girls' bathroom…
但在女厕所…
Those posters were brutal, right?
那些传单真是吓人 对吧？
What is all this?
这都是什么？
IWASAKI IS TRASH
（岩崎是社会的垃圾）
SHOPLIFTER NO MERCY FOR IWASAKI
（小偷 绝不放过岩崎）
He did this…
是他…
KAEDE BADMINTON TOURNAMENT
（枫羽球大赛）
DELETE
（删除）
Huh? The teachers aren't here today.
咦？那些老师今天不在
-Kaede! -Usually the principal and chairman come.
-枫！ -通常校长和理事长都会来
Something happened with the fire.
火灾那边出了点事
They're all at the school.
他们全都在学校
I wonder if they caught the culprit.
不知道他们抓到犯人了没
-Coach Kashiwagi is here. -Where?
-柏木教练来了 -在哪？
Up front in the central block.
在中间那区的前排
Iwasaki!
岩崎
ROUND ONE TATSUMI GAKUEN VS SEIBUDAI CHIBA
（第一回合 龙海学园对上南武台千叶）
Cover me.
拜托你了
Nice.
很好
Game. First game won by Tatsumi Gakuen. 21-5.
结束 第一局 龙海学园胜出 21比5
-Is that the truth? -Yes, I set the fire.
-真的吗？ -是的 火是我放的
Why would you do that?
你为什么这样做？
Mr. Sakuragi scolded me and I got mad.
被樱木老师骂了之后 我很生气
After my delivery, I snuck into the school.
送餐后 我溜进学校
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
School rules say we have to report it to the police.
根据校规 我们必须报警
-Yes, we do. -I'll come along.
-是啊 -我和你一起去
Finally, the Kimitsunishi match.
终于 和君津西的比赛
Look, the first day of a regional tournament.
你们看 地区赛的第一天
Seinan's Kashiwagi and many other big university coaches.
青南大学的柏木 和其它顶尖大学的教练
Everyone's watching this game. No, they're watching you.
大家都在看这场比赛 不 他们在看你们
This game will decide your future.
今天的比赛将决定你们的未来
Especially Iwasaki's Seinan spot. Get it today!
尤其是岩崎 青南大学的推荐名额 今天就拿下吧！
Yes, sir.
是
Let's go.
走吧
ROUND TWO IWASAKI-KIYONO VS YAMANO-UKITA
（第二回合 岩崎与清野对上山野与浮田）
Get it!
追上去！
Nail it!
上吧！
Rie.
利惠
Thanks.
谢谢
Are you okay?
你没事吧？
-Kaede! -Ref!
-枫！ -裁判！
I'm fine.
我没事
Hey, Iwasaki!
喂 岩井
I just got a cramp.
我抽筋了
Go back, please.
快恢复原状 拜托了
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
I'm okay.
我没事
I can play.
我可以继续
Alright, do it!
好 加油！
Yes, sir.
是
-Iwasaki, are you okay? -I'm okay.
-岩井 你没事吧？ -我没事
Kaede, I'll take care of it. Defend from there.
枫 交给我吧 你在那里守着
Sorry.
对不起
Alright!
好！
Ref.
裁判
We forfeit the game.
我们放弃比赛
What?!
什么？
Tatsumi Gakuen dropped out.
龙海学园 退出比赛
Coach. Let me play.
教练 请让我继续
Idiot. Forfeiting because of injury looks better to Kashiwagi.
笨蛋 受伤弃赛 对柏木来说比较好看
I did it for you.
我是为了你才这么做的
Can you play your singles if you tape it?
你贴了胶布后 最后的单打可以上场吗？
Yeah, if I take a painkiller I'll be okay.
可以 吃点止痛药我就会没事了
I think you should sit it out.
我觉得你应该别参加
What, you? Outsiders aren't allowed in here.
你干嘛？外人不允许进来这里
Sir, Okamoto and Abe are starting.
老师 冈本和阿部快开始了
-Okay, I'll go soon. -Sir.
-知道了 我这就过去 -好
Ice it as long as you can.
尽可能冰久一些
Okay.
好
Come with me.
跟我来
Hey, let me go.
等一下 放开我
No. Come with me.
好了 跟我来
I won't! This is an important match.
我不要 这可是个重要的比赛
You can't. Forget it.
你不会赢的 放弃吧
If it's about the shoplifting, just say that.
如果这和偷东西有关 你就直说吧
There's no proof anymore.
都没有证据了
You set the fire.
是你放的火吧
You wanted to delete the video and set the fire.
你想清除掉录影 所以放火
Well, Seto is saying he did it.
这个嘛 濑户说是他干的
Seto?
濑户？
Two people showed up on the security footage from that night.
那晚的监控录像里出现了两个人
Seto and you.
濑户和你
Why isn't it here?
怎么不在这里？
Kaede!
枫！
Were you practicing this late?
你训练到那么晚吗？
I'm going to look for that video in his tent.
我要去他的帐篷里找那段录像
-Don't worry. -No!
-所以放心吧 -不要
You didn't…
你 该不会…
Seto heard from Mizuno that you were caught on camera.
濑户听水野说你被监控拍到了
He suddenly said he'd confess.
就忽然说要自首了
I guess to protect you.
也许是为了保护你
Hey!
喂
Kaede!
枫！
-Dad. -Kaede!
-爸爸 -枫！
Mom.
妈妈
Did you do something to your right knee?
你刚才不会伤到右膝了吧？
She didn't do something, she's been doing it.
不是才伤到 是早就受伤了
The meniscus on your right knee is damaged badly.
右膝盖的半月板磨损得很厉害
It's pretty severe.
相当严重
If you had kept up like this, it would have gotten worse.
这样继续下去的话 情况会变得更糟
Why did you let it get this bad?
为什么你之前一直放任不管呢？
We can remove your meniscus with surgery,
我们能通过手术摘除你的半月板
but it will make your knee unstable.
但这会减少你膝盖的稳定性
In sports like badminton where you need a lot of knee control,
在羽毛球这种需要 大量膝盖控制的运动中
you might not be able to play like you do--
你可能没法表现得像之前一样…
Is there… is there another way?
有没有其它办法？
There's PRP therapy.
有个叫PRP的疗法
It's regenerative medicine, a new technology.
那属于再生医疗 是一种新技术
It doesn't result in any scarring,
它不会留疤
and prosthetics are not put in the body.
也不会在体内植入假体
We might be able to return it to how it was.
有恢复到之前状态的可能
-Okay… -However…
-这样的话… -不过…
It's not recommended for students who are still growing.
这种疗法不建议 用在正发育的初高中生身上
So we would start therapy after you graduate high school.
所以我们会在你 高中毕业后再开始治疗
You'd also need a year of physiotherapy.
还需要一年的物理治疗
So not for two years…
也就是要两年…
But just be aware.
但要知道
This therapy has varied results.
这种疗法会的效果因人而异
You may not recover well enough to compete again.
你可能没法康复到运动员的程度
There's no guarantee.
我们没法保证
Why did you hide it?
你为什么隐瞒？
Top athletes must care for injuries immediately.
处理伤痛是顶尖运动员的基本条件
I'm sorry.
对不起
Quit the badminton club.
退出羽球社
That coach doesn't even notice injuries.
我们没法相信连伤都看不出的教练
I'll find a personal trainer who knows therapy.
我会找一个懂得治疗的私人教练
For now, focus on strength training.
现阶段先集中力量训练
Something that doesn't strain your knee.
不会给你膝盖带来负担的运动
Understood?
明白吗？
Yes, sir.
明白
Two years. You'd make it in time for the next Olympics.
两年 你还能赶上奥运会
What? What's funny?
干嘛？哪里好笑了？
You're a joke, that's what.
你真是个笑话
You don't care about her feelings, just her athletic career.
你不在乎女儿的感受 只在乎运动生涯
Her future is at stake!
她的未来现在可是岌岌可危！
We're doing all we can for her!
我们在尽力为她做些什么！
Is it really for her?
真的是为了她吗？
Who are you? So rude!
你是哪位？真是无礼！
What does she want to do? Isn't that most important?
她想做什么 这难道不是最重要的吗？
She could take this injury as a sign to leave sports.
她可以把这次受伤 当作离开体育的信号
Preposterous! I don't need an outsider talking to me like this.
荒谬！我不需要一个外人来教育我
-This is my daughter's problem. -Yes, your daughter's problem.
-这是我女儿的问题 -对 你女儿的问题
Not yours.
不是你的
Iwasaki.
岩崎
What you do is up to you.
你要怎么做 你来决定
That's awfully noisy. Turn off your phone.
从刚才开始就吵死了 手机关掉
It's Kiyono.
是清野
Answer it. It could be about the recruiter.
快接 可能是推荐的事
Okay.
好
Hello, Kaede?
喂 枫？
Yeah.
嗯
-How was the game? -I won.
-比赛怎么样？ -我赢了
But how's your injury?
你的伤怎么样？
I tore my meniscus.
我的半月板撕裂了
I knew it.
果然
Coach, it's her meniscus.
教练 是半月板
Hey, Kaede.
那个 枫
I talked to Coach Kashiwagi.
我和柏木教练聊了
He said a torn meniscus means you won't play for a while.
他说半月板撕裂 代表你有一阵子都没法上场了
I, uh, I'm sorry.
我…很对不起
They asked me to take the spot in your place.
他们让我顶替你的推荐名额
Oh.
这样啊
I'm really sorry.
真的很对不起
At a tough time like this for you.
在你那么艰难的时候
Yeah. See ya.
嗯 再见
What did she say?
她说什么？
Rie got into Seinan University.
利惠进了青南大学
-What! -Pathetic.
-什么！ -真是可悲
Getting bested by a less-skilled rival…
被能力更差的对手打败…
-Because you hid an injury like an idiot! -I'm sorry.
-就因为你像白痴一样隐瞒伤势！ -对不起
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
对不起！
-Sorry doesn't cut it! Do you understand? -Not here!
-对不起是没有用的！你明白吗？ -别在这里
We're going home. You need to cool off.
我们先回家了 你要冷静一下
Hey, where are you going?
喂 你去哪里？
The police. Seto turned himself in, right?
警局 濑户自首了 对吧？
I'm going to tell them I did it.
我现在去告诉他们 是我干的
He won't be there.
他不会在那里
Right about now, he's probably helping out at the restaurant.
他现在应该在店里帮忙吧
School rules say we have to report it to the police.
根据校规 我们必须报警
Yes, we do.
是啊
I'll come along.
我和你一起去
Wait.
等一下
What is it?
又怎么了？
Before we go to the police, shouldn't we include his family
去警局之前 我们是不是 也应该把他家人参与进来
and discuss this well?
好好谈谈？
In Japan, arson is a serious crime.
在日本 纵火可是重罪
It can result in a sentence equal to that of a murder.
判决可能会和谋杀一样重
Murder!
谋杀！
Even in a case like this, where it was small,
就算是这样的小案子
the punishment for arson of an inhabited building can be death,
在有人居住的建筑物纵火 刑罚可以是死刑
or life imprisonment.
或是终身监禁
Considering a student's future,
考虑学生的未来
and guiding them is the role of a school.
并引导他们是学校的责任
Even so…
即便如此…
The school can't just cover it up.
学校也不能掩盖这件事
It's already been taken care of.
这件事已经解决了
Mr. Sakuragi!
樱木老师
The fire was 100% my fault, without a doubt.
那场火百分之百是我的错 毋须质疑
I've already spoken to the police, and they gave me a strong warning.
我已经和警察说过话了 他们也给了我严厉的警告
That's it.
就这样
You don't have to cover for me.
你不用掩护我
-Huh? -You covered for Mr. Sakuragi?
-咦？ -你掩护樱木老师？
If I were gone,
如果我不在了
he'd lose his chance to try out for UTokyo.
他就会失去上东大的机会
He's always been gunning for UTokyo.
他一直都把东大当目标
What?
什么？
Anyway, Chairman…
无论如何 理事长
As long as a student is trying for UTokyo,
只要还有一位学生在为东大努力
we respect that freedom.
我们就要尊重这一份自由
And you'll keep the Special Course, right?
你会留着东大专科 对吧？
So he's okay. Good.
所以他没事 太好了
But what about badminton?
羽毛球那里怎么样？
I can't just quit that easily.
我不能就这样放弃
My mom and dad didn't make it to the Olympics.
我爸妈没能打进奥运会
It's their dream for me to go.
他们的梦想就是我能打进
They've spent their lives supporting me.
他们一辈子都在支持我
I held my first racket when I was two.
我两岁时就握了我第一个球拍
Since then, badminton has been my whole life.
那以后 羽球就成了我人生的全部
I've devoted everything to it.
我为它奉献了一切
I'd get recruited to a famous university,
被知名大学招收
and aim for the Olympics.
还有争取参加奥运会
I've…
我…
I've only ever thought about that life.
我只想象过那种人生
What should I do now?
我接下来该怎么办？
How will I live my life without badminton?
没有羽球 我要怎么活下去？
How indeed.
这个嘛
It's your life. You decide.
这是你的人生 你来决定
It's not that simple.
没那么简单
I've always done what my parents said. I entered a strong school.
一直以来 我都跟着爸妈说的做 进了名校
-I did what my coach told me… -That's not all true.
-教练叫我练习我就练… -这不是真的
You made those choices, didn't you?
那些选择是你自己做的 不是吗？
You gave your life to badminton.
你把人生献给了羽毛球
You hid your injury for that spot.
为了推荐名额隐瞒伤势
You shoplifted to cope. Did your parents tell you to do that?
你用偷东西纾解压力 你父母有让你这么做吗？
No, right? You decided.
没有吧？那全是你的决定
It's your responsibility.
是你的责任
Don't blame others.
不要把责任推给别人
Yes, sir.
是
But your injury, that alone,
但你的伤 就这一件事
wasn't all your fault.
不完全是你的责任
-Huh? -Let's go catch the culprit.
-什么？ -我们去把犯人抓出来吧
Hey!
喂！
-We're you waiting? -You're late.
-抱歉 等很久了吗？ -你迟到了
Sorry, a lot of stuff happened.
不好意思 发生了很多事情
-Here. -Iwai?
-给 -岩井？
You put one on too. Here.
你也戴上 给
-Get on. -Where are we going?
-上来吧 -我们去哪？
Just trust my driving.
相信我就好
C'mon.
走吧
Hey! Drive safely!
喂！小心点骑！
Hey. They're in here.
你好 他们在里面
-Thanks. -The cell coverage here is really bad.
-谢谢 -这里的信号很弱
So they haven't contacted anyone.
他们没办法联络别人
-Also, here. -You've done well.
-还有 这个 -做得好
-I'll buy you some ramen next time. -Nice!
-下次请你吃拉面 -好！
I'm opening it.
我开门啦
It's open! We're saved.
终于开了 我们得救啦！
You guys? And Iwasaki too?
你们？还有岩井？
You did this?
是你干的？
-What are you thinking?! -I asked them to.
-你想干什么？ -我让他们做的
I had something I really needed to ask you two.
我有些事一定要问你们两位
What?
什么？
Yeah, but it really went well.
是啊 但那真的很顺利
Thank you very much.
谢谢
I want to know, did you run into her on purpose?
我想知道 你是不是故意跑向她的？
Well, I'll leave that to your imagination.
这个嘛 我就留给你自己想象了
At any rate, that clinched it.
无论如何 事情就这样解决了
I was really surprised. I can't believe it was that bad.
但我也很惊讶 没想到枫的情况那么糟
I told you, her knee was reaching its limit.
我跟你说过 她的膝盖已经到达极限
That's why I ran her ragged on purpose,
所以我才故意让她跑得筋疲力竭
and gave her all that tough practice.
还有做那些艰苦的训练
I can really depend on you.
不愧是老师 真是可靠
I got recruited thanks to you.
多亏老师 我拿到推荐名额了
Yeah, so maybe we can meet outside sometimes…
所以说 我们偶尔可以在外面见见面…
Nope!
不可以哦！
N-No, no, you've got it all wrong…
不 你完全误会了…
No? What about it?
误会？我们误会了什么？
You want to explain?
你要不要解释？
Alright, then shall I explain?
那我来解释吧？
You pretended not to see Iwasaki's injury.
你假装没发现岩崎的伤
In fact, you gave her exercises that stressed her knee.
不止如此 你还刻意安排她 多做对膝盖有负担的运动
You made Iwasaki's injury worse.
你让岩崎的伤变得更严重
To ensure that Kiyono got the Seinan University spot.
以确保清野得到青南大学的推荐名额
You only get one place at Seinan.
青南大学的推荐名额只有一个
Iwasaki was practically a shoo-in, but as a spare,
岩崎基本上十拿九稳 但作为替补
Kiyono's name had come up.
清野的名字出现了
So to you, Kiyono, Iwasaki was in the way.
所以清野 岩崎对你是个阻碍
Those posters put up everywhere, that was you, right?
那些到处都是的传单 是你干的吧？
Huh?
什么？
Did you…
难道你…
What's he going to do?
那家伙到底想做什么？
Hey, is someone there?
喂 那里有人吗？
Hey!
喂！
Once Kiyono got recruited,
清野获得名额后
I figured you'd expose yourself.
我想你应该会露出马脚
I got Iwai and Kohashi to stand lookout.
我让岩井和小桥去查
And they managed to take this video.
于是他们就拍到了这视频
This is bullshit!
胡说八道！
You think you can do this and get away with it?
你以为你这么做会没事？
Bullshit?
胡说八道？
That's Iwasaki's line!
那是岩崎的台词吧！
To steal the Seinan placement,
为了偷走青南大学的推荐名额
you crushed a talented athlete's future.
你毁掉了一个运动员的未来
You ignored Iwasaki's injury.
你无视岩崎的伤
Yet you're an adviser at a strong school like this?
还配当名校的顾问吗？
Not only as a teacher,
不止作为教师
you're a failure as a human!
你根本不配当人！
I-Iwasaki.
岩…岩崎
How stupid.
好愚蠢
What was the point of all my hard work?
我所有的努力都是为了什么？
I was fighting alone.
我独自战斗着
I thought I was hiding my injury.
我以为自己藏着伤势
I wanted that spot, staying late every night.
我想要推荐名额 每天练习到很晚
You even burned my tent.
你甚至还烧了我的帐篷
I don't know where you got that idea.
我不知道你怎么想的
I got that video and erased it immediately.
我拿到那段录像后 就马上删掉了
These days, you don't know how people will use videos.
这个年代 你没法知道 其他人会用视频做什么坏事
I even deleted it from the store's data.
我甚至把它从便利店的数据库删除了
If it gets out, I'm in trouble too.
如果这传出去 我也会有麻烦
The problem with shoplifting,
偷东西的问题是
you do it once and you can't escape it.
你做过一次就会没法逃离
You thought once wasn't a big deal.
你以为一块巧克力没什么大不了
But that one thing,
但那一个东西
it'll ruin your life.
它会毁了你的人生
Just like badminton,
就像羽毛球
people who don't follow the rules
那些不遵守规矩的人
lose at life.
会输掉人生
Yes, sir.
是
Well, I shoplifted a lot back in the day, so I shouldn't talk.
我以前常偷东西 没资格说那么多
Anyway, when did you notice my injury?
话说 你是什么时候发现我受伤的？
When you tripped on the stairs.
你在楼梯绊倒的时候
Kaede!
枫！
You said it was a cramp.
你当时说是抽筋
Your torn meniscus caught on your knee, and got locked up, right?
你撕裂的半月板夹在膝盖上 然后被锁住了 对吧？
I had the same experience long ago.
我很久以前也经历过
-That's why I quit basketball. -Oh.
-所以我才没打篮球了 -这样啊
I bet my life on it, and I suddenly lost it.
我把人生都赌进去 然后忽然就输了
I was so frustrated, I went wild with a biker gang for a while.
我当时很受挫 就和一群暴走族混了一阵子
From that point,
那以后
how did you recover?
你怎么振作起来的？
Study.
学习
When you don't have any money, it's all you can do.
没钱也能做的 只有这件事了
As I frantically worked at it,
我疯狂地奋斗时
I realized it was a shortcut.
我发现这是条捷径
Before I knew it, my frustration had disappeared.
在发现之前 我的挫败感已经消失了
That's just what worked for me.
不过那只是对我有效的方法
You decide your path.
你的道路由你来决定
You're aiming for the national championships.
你们的目标是全国赛
We can't lose now.
我们现在不能输
Do it for Iwasaki, who can't play from her injury.
为了受伤不能上场的岩崎
Show them the results of all your practice, okay?
让他们看看你们的训练成果 听到没？
-Coach. -What is it?
-教练 -什么？
Good morning.
早上好
Why are you here?
你怎么在这里？
Today I'll be here to support behind the scenes.
今天我会担任后援协助大家
Thanks for having me.
请多多关照了
Thank you.
请多关照
Okay, let's get ready. Let's go.
好 快去准备 走吧
Yes, sir!
是！
Kaede.
枫
What are you doing?
你在干嘛？
Even if I can't play,
就算我不能上场
I just want to do what I can.
我也想尽一己之力
You're scheming something.
你在谋划些什么吧
TATSUMI GAKUEN VS GOI HIGH SCHOOL
（龙海学园对上五井高中）
KIYONO-YAMADA VS HORIE-INAGAKI
（清野与山田对上堀江与稻垣）
What's going on?
这是怎么回事？
Oh, you came! Thanks.
你们来了 谢谢
Why isn't Kaede scheduled to play?
为什么不是枫上场？
She forfeited due to injury.
她因为受伤弃赛了
-Injury? -Iwasaki's injury.
-受伤？ -岩崎受伤了
It'll take two years to play like she did before.
她需要两年才能回到以前的表现
Even then, it might not go back to how it was.
也可能没法完全恢复那种状态
-No… -Even so.
-不会吧… -尽管这样
She hasn't given up her dreams as an athlete.
她还是没有放弃作为运动员的梦想
She's doing all she can right now.
她正在尽她所能
Pretty amazing.
很了不起呢
TATSUMI GAKUEN VS GOI HIGH SCHOOL
（龙海学园 五井高中）
KIYONO VS KOTANI FINAL DECIDING MATCH
（清野对上古谷 冠军总决赛）
Game. First game won by
结束 第一局
Goi High School, 21-17.
五井高中胜出 21比17
Good game.
辛苦了
You got the Seinan spot and look at you.
拿到了青南大学的推荐名额 就只有这种程度吗？
Kashiwagi is watching. You're embarrassing me.
柏木在那里看着 你在丢我的脸
You've got to win this. Look sharp out there.
你一定要赢 给我小心点
Yes, sir.
是
-Rie. -Huh?
-利惠 -干什么？
I'm not mad.
我没有生气
I was the one who hid my injury.
隐瞒伤势的人是我
I've been playing since preschool.
我从幼儿园就开始打羽球了
You're the best partner I've ever had.
你是我有过最好的搭档
It's true.
是真的
Really.
真的
You are strong.
你很强
You're strong!
你很强！
Believe in yourself.
相信你自己
Don't cry! Win!
别哭！要赢啊！
And anyway.
还有
You.
你
You can't let it end like this.
不能让比赛就这样结束
It's unacceptable for you to lose.
输了的话 我不会原谅你
Go do it for the team!
为了队伍赢下这场！
Yeah!
好耶！
Game. Match won by Tatsumi Gakuen.
结束 龙海学园胜出比赛
You did it!
你做到了！
We won! We won!
我们赢了！
Hip hip, hooray! Hooray!
准备 万岁！
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
万岁！
Hoist up Kiyono!
把清野抬起来！
Kiyono!
清野！
Ready?
准备
Hooray! Hooray! Hooray!
万岁！
Alright.
好了
Oh, what's this?
哦 这是什么？
I'm forgetting something.
我忘记了
Okay…
来…
I decided.
我决定了
Decided what?
决定什么？
You want to sue your coach?
你要起诉那个教练？
We could crush him legally.
我们有好几种用法律击垮他的方法
Oh, I won't do that.
我不会这么做
Without that coach, the team would fall apart.
没了那个教练 羽球队也会分崩离析
Even if he's like that, he's an excellent coach.
尽管他这样 他的确是个优秀的教练
But after I recover, I won't hold back.
但康复后 我不会退缩了
You're a softie.
你真是心软
-Sir. -Hm?
-老师 -嗯？
I…
我…
I want to get into UTokyo.
我想考上东大
I want to study sports medicine at UTokyo.
我想在东大学运动医学
I'll recover, and go to the Olympics.
我会康复 然后参加奥运会
After I retire as an athlete,
退役后
I'll support young athletes with sports medicine.
我会以运动医疗支持年轻的运动员
That's…
那…
That's my new life plan.
那是我新的人生计划
Stop talking nonsense!
别胡说八道了！
With a mixed motivation like that, you'll never get into UTokyo.
动机那么复杂 你永远都上不了东大
Right…
也是…
But I'll tell you this.
但我可以跟你说
Compared to becoming an Olympic athlete,
比起成为奥运会运动员
it's much easier to get into UTokyo.
上东大容易多了
I don't play to lose.
我比赛不是为了输
Bring it on.
这样正好
Even so.
不过
I have to do something first.
我有些事情得先做
-Hey, Seto. -Hey.
-嘿 濑户 -嘿
You guys.
我说
When did you become his minions?
你们什么时候变成他的小弟了？
He might actually be a good dude, right?
那家伙可能是个好人 对吧？
Why don't you knock it off?
不如你停手吧？
Kaede's thing got worked out too.
枫的事情也解决了
-I'm home. -Oh, hey.
-我回来了 -你回来啦
Did you quit the club?
你退出羽球社了吗？
Yeah.
嗯
I got you an interview with a private coach next week.
我帮你安排了 下周和一位私人教练面试
So you…
所以你…
-What's this? -Ah.
-这是什么？ -啊
Study materials?
参考书？
Well, I just thought I'd study a little.
这个嘛 我想我也可以学习一下
Do you have time to take it easy like that?
你有时间这样放松吗？
Studying is for people with no talent.
学习是没才能的人做的事
You don't have to spend time on a common thing like that.
你不能把时间花在 这种普通人做的事上
Practice is more important.
训练更重要
Got it?
明白了吗？
Yes, sir.
是
I'm impressed you found me.
我没想到你能找到我
I asked an acquaintance teaching at UTokyo.
我问了在东大教书的熟人
I got them to see if your name was on the rolls.
请他看看你的名字在不在名单上
You managed to get into UTokyo after all.
最后你还是上了东大
Yes, it took two years after that.
是 那之后又用了两年
I see.
原来
Congratulations.
恭喜
I don't want what happened to ever happen again.
我不想再发生这样的事了
I said I'd never do educational consulting again.
因此说过我不会再当教学顾问
That's what I thought.
我曾经这样想
However.
但是
I'm starting to think,
我开始在想
I want to go back to Toranomon.
我想要回去虎之门
I want to work for a noble cause one more time.
我想再次为一个崇高目的而努力
I want your blessing.
我想得到你的祝福
What are you saying, sir?
你在说什么 老师？
Don't worry about me.
别顾虑我
Go on and do it.
尽管去做吧
I always wanted to apologize to you.
我一直都想向你道歉
I was out of my mind.
我当时失去了理智
It's not something you can just apologize for, I know.
虽然这种事情不是道歉就没事了
I'm really…
真的…
sorry.
很对不起
That's what I told him.
这就是我跟他说的话
It's so convenient.
真是方便
Mr. Sakuragi being back in business makes our job easier.
樱木老师回来 我们的工作就容易多了
So he's finally gotten motivated.
所以他终于找到动力了
I'm sure he found a student.
他肯定找到了感兴趣的学生
Tatsumi Gakuen.
龙海学园
Things are getting interesting.
事情变得有趣了
Yes.
对啊
I will crush them.
我绝对会毁掉他们
No matter what.
一定
Everything has meaning.
每一件事都有它的意义
Why is it written that way?
为什么问题这么问？
See it from every angle to get the substance.
从不同的角度去看 去寻找本质
You really think you'll pass? At that level?
你真的觉得你能考上？就凭这水平？
Shut up!
闭嘴！
Shall we have a contest?
我们要不要来场比赛？
Let's do it.
来吧
Become a YouTuber.
你们俩当油管博主
You two do Twitter.
你们俩负责推特
-Are you studying? -It's nothing.
-你在学习吗？ -没有啦
We might really win!
我们可能真的会赢！
There are advantages to being idiots.
当笨蛋是有一些好处的
Sir, do you know something?
莫非老师你知道些什么？
When you four pass, this tree will be in full bloom.
等你们四个都考上东大的时候 这棵树刚好也会开满花
A Dragon Zakura?
龙樱？
There's a chance we could win?
但我们有机会赢吗？
There are ways.
有好几种方法
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻译：赵慈宇